<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apache SkyWalking – Logs</title>
    <link>/tags/logs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Logs on Apache SkyWalking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/tags/logs/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: SourceMarker: Continuous Feedback for Developers</title>
      <link>/blog/2021-03-16-continuous-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021-03-16-continuous-feedback/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;SM_IDE-APM.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Alt Text&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcemarker.dev&#34;&gt;SourceMarker&lt;/a&gt; is an open-source continuous feedback IDE plugin built on top of Apache SkyWalking, a popular open-source APM system with monitoring, tracing, and diagnosing capabilities for distributed software systems. SkyWalking, a truly holistic system, provides the means for automatically producing, storing, and querying software operation metrics. It requires little to no code changes to implement and is lightweight enough to be used in production. By itself, SkyWalking is a formidable force in the realm of continuous monitoring technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SourceMarker, leveraging the continuous monitoring functionality provided by SkyWalking, creates continuous feedback technology by automatically linking software operation metrics to source code and displaying feedback directly inside of the IDE. While currently only supporting JetBrains-based IDEs and JVM-based programming languages, SourceMarker may be extended to support any number of programming languages and IDEs. Using SourceMarker, software developers can understand and validate software operation inside of their IDE. Instead of charts that indicate the health of the application, software developers can view the health of individual source code components and interpret software operation metrics from a much more familiar perspective. Such capabilities improve productivity as time spent continuously context switching from development to monitoring would be eliminated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;logging&#34;&gt;Logging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;SM_Logging.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Logging&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The benefits of continuous feedback technology are immediately apparent with the ability to view and search logs directly from source code. Instead of tailing log files or viewing logs through the browser, SourceMarker allows software developers to navigate production logs just as easily as they navigate source code. By using the source code as the primary perspective for navigating logs, SourceMarker allows software developers to view logs specific to any package, class, method, or line directly from the context of the source code which resulted in those logs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tracing&#34;&gt;Tracing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;SM_Tracing.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Tracing&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, continuous feedback technology offers software developers a deeper understanding of software by explicitly tying the implicit software operation to source code. Instead of visualizing software traces as Gantt charts, SourceMarker allows software developers to step through trace stacks while automatically resolving trace tags and logs. With SourceMarker, software developers can navigate production software traces in much the same way one debugs local applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;alerting&#34;&gt;Alerting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;SM_Alerting.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Alerting&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, continuous feedback technology keeps software developers aware of production software operation. Armed with an APM-powered IDE, every software developer can keep track of the behavior of any method, class, package, and even the entire application itself. Moreover, this allows for source code to be the medium through which production bugs are made evident, thereby creating the feasibility of source code with the ability to self-diagnose and convey its own health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;download-sourcemarker&#34;&gt;Download SourceMarker&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SourceMarker aims to bridge the theoretical and empirical practices of software development through continuous feedback. The goal is to make developing software with empirical data feel natural and intuitive, creating more complete software developers that understand the entire software development cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sourceplusplus/sourcemarker&#34;&gt;https://github.com/sourceplusplus/sourcemarker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project is still early in its development, so if you think of any ways to improve SourceMarker, please let us know.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Apache SkyWalking 8.4: Logs, VM Monitoring, and Dynamic Configurations at Agent Side</title>
      <link>/blog/skywalking8-4-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/skywalking8-4-release/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;heading.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Origin: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tetrate.io/blog/skywalking-8-4/&#34;&gt;Tetrate.io blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Apache SkyWalking team today announced the 8.4 release is generally available. This release fills the gap between all previous versions of SkyWalking and the logging domain area.
The release also advances SkyWalking’s capabilities  for infrastructure observability, starting with virtual machine monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SkyWalking has historically focused on the tracing and metrics fields of observability.
As its features for tracing, metrics and service level monitoring have become more and more powerful and stable, the SkyWalking team has started to explore new scenarios covered by observability.
Because service performance is reflected in the logs, and is highly impacted by the infrastructure on which it runs, SkyWalking brings these two fields into the 8.4 release.
This release blog briefly introduces the two new features as well as some other notable changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;logs&#34;&gt;Logs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metrics, tracing, and logging are considered the three pillars of observability [1]. SkyWalking had the full features of metrics and tracing prior to 8.4; today, as 8.4 is released, the last piece of the jigsaw is now in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;figure01.png&#34; alt=&#34;Logs Collected By SkyWalking&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: Logs Collected By SkyWalking&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;figure02.png&#34; alt=&#34;Logs Collected By SkyWalking&#34;&gt;
Figure 2: Logs Collected By SkyWalking&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Java agent firstly provides SDKs to enhance the widely-used logging frameworks, log4j (1.x and 2.x) [2] and logback [3], and send the logs to the SkyWalking backend (OAP).
The latter is able to collect logs from wherever the protocol is  implemented.
This is not a big deal, but when it comes to the correlation between logs and traces, the traditional solution is to print the trace IDs in the logs, and pick the IDs in the error logs to query the related traces.
SkyWalking just simplifies the workflow by correlating the logs and traces natively. Navigating between traces and their related logs is as simple as clicking a button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;figure03.png&#34; alt=&#34;Correlation Between Logs and Traces&#34;&gt;
Figure 3: Correlation Between Logs and Traces&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;infrastructure-monitoring&#34;&gt;Infrastructure Monitoring&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SkyWalking is known as an application performance monitoring tool. One of the most important factors that impacts the application’s performance is the infrastructure on which the application runs.
In the 8.4 release, we added the monitoring metrics of virtual machines into the dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;figure04.png&#34; alt=&#34;VM Metrics&#34;&gt;
Figure 4: VM Metrics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fundamental metrics such as &lt;code&gt;CPU Used&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Memory Used&lt;/code&gt;,  &lt;code&gt;Disk Read / Write&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Network Usage&lt;/code&gt; are available on the dashboard.
And as usual, those metrics are also available to be configured as alarm triggers when needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dynamic-configurations-at-agent-side&#34;&gt;Dynamic Configurations at Agent Side&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dynamic configuration at the backend side has long existed in SkyWalking for several versions. Now, it finally comes to the agent side!
Prior to 8.4, you’d have to restart the target services when you modify some configuration items of the agent &amp;ndash; for instance, sampling rate (agent side), ignorable endpoint paths, etc. Now, say goodbye to rebooting.
Modifying configurations is not the only usage of the dynamic configuration mechanism. The latter gives countless possibilities to the agent side in terms of dynamic behaviours, e.g. enabling / disabling plugins, enabling / disabling the whole agent, etc. Just imagine!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;grouped-service-topology&#34;&gt;Grouped Service Topology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This enhancement is from the UI. SkyWalking backend supports grouping the services by user-defined dimensions. In a real world use case, the services are usually grouped by business group or department. When a developer opens the topology map, out of hundreds of services, he or she may just want to focus on the services in charge. The grouped service topology comes to the rescue: one can now choose to display only services belonging to a specified group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;figure05.png&#34; alt=&#34;Grouped Service Topology&#34;&gt;
Figure 5: Grouped Service Topology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-notable-enhancements&#34;&gt;Other Notable Enhancements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agent: resolves domain names to look up backend service IP addresses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backend: meter receiver supports meter analysis language (MAL).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backend: several CVE fixes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backend: supports Envoy &lt;code&gt;{AccessLog,Metrics}Service&lt;/code&gt; API V3 and adopts MAL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[1] &lt;a href=&#34;https://peter.bourgon.org/blog/2017/02/21/metrics-tracing-and-logging.html&#34;&gt;https://peter.bourgon.org/blog/2017/02/21/metrics-tracing-and-logging.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[2] &lt;a href=&#34;https://logging.apache.org/log4j/2.x/&#34;&gt;https://logging.apache.org/log4j/2.x/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[3] &lt;a href=&#34;http://logback.qos.ch&#34;&gt;http://logback.qos.ch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;additional-resources&#34;&gt;Additional Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read more about the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apache/skywalking/blob/v8.4.0/changes/changes-8.4.0.md&#34;&gt;SkyWalking 8.4 release highlights&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get more SkyWalking updates on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ASFSkyWalking&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
