<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apache SkyWalking – Video</title>
    <link>/tags/video/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Video on Apache SkyWalking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/tags/video/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: [Video] Coffee &#43; Software with Josh Long - Apache SkyWalking with Sheng Wu and Apache ShardingSphere with Trista Pan</title>
      <link>/blog/2023-12-04-coffee&#43;software-with-josh-long/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2023-12-04-coffee&#43;software-with-josh-long/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;🚀 Dive into the World of Cutting-Edge Technology with Apache&amp;rsquo;s Finest! 🌐 Join me today as we embark on an exhilarating journey with two of Apache&amp;rsquo;s most brilliant minds - Sheng Wu and Trista Pan. We&amp;rsquo;re exploring the realms of Apache SkyWalking and Apache ShardingSphere, two groundbreaking initiatives that are reshaping the landscape of open-source technology. 🌟&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this exclusive session, we delve deep into Apache SkyWalking - an innovative observability platform that&amp;rsquo;s revolutionizing how we monitor and manage distributed systems in the cloud. Witness firsthand how SkyWalking is empowering developers and organizations to gain unparalleled insights into their applications, ensuring performance, reliability, and efficient troubleshooting. 🛰️🔍&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;rsquo;s more! We&amp;rsquo;re also unveiling the secrets of Apache ShardingSphere, a dynamic distributed database ecosystem. Learn how ShardingSphere is making waves in the world of big data, offering scalable, high-performance solutions for data sharding, encryption, and more. This is your gateway to understanding how these technologies are pivotal in handling massive data sets across various industries. 🌐💾&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a developer, tech enthusiast, or just curious about the future of open-source technology, this is a conversation you don&amp;rsquo;t want to miss! Get ready to be inspired and informed as we unlock new possibilities and applications of Apache SkyWalking and ShardingSphere. 🚀🌟&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join us, and let&amp;rsquo;s decode the future together!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/96ZacpHObmM&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please join and follow Josh&amp;rsquo;s 龙之春 Youtube &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@coffeesoftware&#34;&gt;Coffee + Software with Josh Long&lt;/a&gt; Channel to learn more about technology and open source from telanted engineers and industry leads.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: [Video] Distributed tracing demo using Apache SkyWalking and Kong API Gateway</title>
      <link>/blog/2022-08-11-kongcast-20-distributed-tracing-using-skywalking-kong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022-08-11-kongcast-20-distributed-tracing-using-skywalking-kong/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Observability essential when working with distributed systems. Built on 3 pillars of metrics, logging and
tracing, having the right tools in place to quickly identify and determine the root cause of an issue in production
is imperative. In this Kongcast interview, we explore the benefits of having observability and demo the use of
Apache SkyWalking. We walk through the capabilities that SkyWalking offers out of the box and debug a common HTTP 500
error using the tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew Kew is interviewed by Viktor Gamov, a developer advocate at &lt;a href=&#34;https://konghq.com/&#34;&gt;Kong Inc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew is a highly passionate technologist with over 16 valuable years experience in building server side and cloud
applications. Having spent the majority of his time in the Financial Services domain, his meritocratic rise to CTO of an
Algorithmic Trading firm allowed him to not only steer the business from a technology standpoint, but build robust and
scalable trading algorithms. His mantra is &amp;ldquo;right first time&amp;rdquo;, thus ensuring the projects or clients he is involved in
are left in a better place than they were before he arrived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is the founder of a boutique software consultancy in the United Kingdom, &lt;a href=&#34;https://quadcorps.co.uk&#34;&gt;QuadCorps Ltd&lt;/a&gt;, working in the API and
Integration Ecosystem space and is currently on a residency programme at &lt;a href=&#34;https://konghq.com/&#34;&gt;Kong Inc&lt;/a&gt; as a senior field engineer and
technical account manager working across many of their enterprise strategic accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/r8e9ib0powM&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: [Webinar] SkyWalking 8.x Introduction</title>
      <link>/blog/2021-08-01-skywalking-8-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021-08-01-skywalking-8-intro/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/company/goupaz/&#34;&gt;GOUP&lt;/a&gt; hosted a webinar, and invited &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/wusheng1108&#34;&gt;Sheng Wu&lt;/a&gt; to introduce
Apache SkyWalking. This is a 1.5 hours presentation including the full landscape of Apache SkyWalking 8.x.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter04-session10---apache-skywalking-by-sheng-wu&#34;&gt;Chapter04 Session10 - Apache Skywalking by Sheng Wu&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6lmHU3XtN10&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: [Video] Another backend storage solution for the APM system</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-11-21-apachecon-obs-shardingsphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-11-21-apachecon-obs-shardingsphere/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The APM system provides the tracing or metrics for distributed systems or microservice architectures. Back to APM themselves, they always need backend storage to store the necessary massive data. What are the features required for backend storage? Simple, fewer dependencies, widely used query language, and the efficiency could be into your consideration. Based on that, traditional SQL databases (like MySQL) or NoSQL databases would be better choices. However, this topic will present another backend storage solution for the APM system viewing from NewSQL. Taking Apache Skywalking for instance, this talking will share how to make use of Apache ShardingSphere, a distributed database middleware ecosystem to extend the APM system&amp;rsquo;s storage capability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a senior DBA worked at JD.com, the responsibility is to develop the distributed database and middleware, and the automated management platform for database clusters. As a PMC of Apache ShardingSphere, I am willing to contribute to the OS community and explore the area of distributed databases and NewSQL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OazS_3r3NM4&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: [Video] Improve Apache APISIX observability with Apache SkyWalking</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-11-21-apachecon-obs-apisix/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-11-21-apachecon-obs-apisix/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Apache APISIX is a cloud-native microservices API gateway, delivering the ultimate performance, security, open-source and scalable platform for all your APIs and microservices. Apache SkyWalking: an APM(application performance monitor) system, especially designed for microservices, cloud-native and container-based (Docker, Kubernetes, Mesos) architectures. Through the powerful plug-in mechanism of Apache APISIX, Apache Skywalking is quickly supported, so that we can see the complete life cycle of requests from the edge to the internal service. Monitor and manage each request in a visual way, and improve the observability of the service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DleVJwPs4i4&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: [Video] SourceMarker - Continuous Feedback for Developers</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-11-21-apachecon-obs-sourcemarker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-11-21-apachecon-obs-sourcemarker/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s monitoring solutions are geared towards operational tasks, displaying behavior as time-series graphs inside dashboards and other abstractions. These abstractions are immensely useful but are largely designed for software operators, whose responsibilities require them to think in systems, rather than the underlying source code. This is problematic given that an ongoing trend of software development is the blurring boundaries between building and operating software. This trend makes it increasingly necessary for programming environments to not just support development-centric activities, but operation-centric activities as well. Such is the goal of the feedback-driven development approach. By combining IDE and APM technology, software developers can intuitively explore multiple dimensions of their software simultaneously with continuous feedback about their software from inception to production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brandon Fergerson is an open-source software developer who does not regard himself as a specialist in the field of programming, but rather as someone who is a devoted admirer. He discovered the beauty of programming at a young age and views programming as an art and those who do it well to be artists. He has an affinity towards getting meta and combining that with admiration of programming, has found source code analysis to be exceptionally interesting. Lately, his primary focus involves researching and building AI-based pair programming technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IWounkxhfi0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: [Video] The history of distributed tracing storage</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-11-21-apachecon-obs-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-11-21-apachecon-obs-storage/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, and coupled with the growing adoption of microservices, distributed tracing has emerged as one of the most commonly used monitoring and troubleshooting methodologies. New tracing tools are increasingly being introduced, driving adoption even further. One of these tools is Apache SkyWalking, a popular open-source tracing, and APM platform. This talk explores the history of the SkyWalking storage module, shows the evolution of distributed tracing storage layers, from the traditional relational database to document-based search engine. I hope that this talk contributes to the understanding of history and also that it helps to clarify the different types of storage that are available to organizations today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hongtao Gao is the engineer of tetrate.io and the former Huawei Cloud expert. One of PMC members of Apache SkyWalking and participates in some popular open-source projects such as Apache ShardingSphere and Elastic-Job. He has an in-depth understanding of distributed databases, container scheduling, microservices, ServicMesh, and other technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/iQ0tODBoh1k&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: [Video] Apache grows in China</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-11-21-apachecon-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-11-21-apachecon-keynote/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Sheng Wu is a founding engineer at tetrate.io, leads the observability for service mesh and hybrid cloud. A searcher, evangelist, and developer in the observability, distributed tracing, and APM. He is a member of the Apache Software Foundation. Love open source software and culture. Created the Apache SkyWalking project and being its VP and PMC member. Co-founder and PMC member of Apache ShardingSphere. Also as a PMC member of Apache Incubator and APISIX. He is awarded as Microsoft MVP, Alibaba Cloud MVP, Tencent Cloud TVP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Apache FY2020 report, China is on the top of the download statistics. More China initiated projects joined the incubator, and some of them graduated as the Apache TLP. Sheng joined the Apache community since 2017, in the past 3 years, he witnessed the growth of the open-source culture and Apache way in China.
Many developers have joined the ASF as new contributors, committers, foundation members. Chinese enterprises and companies paid more attention to open source contributions, rather than simply using the project like before. In the keynote, he would share the progress about China embracing the Apache culture, and willing of enhancing the whole Apache community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/26aFGdbZvac&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
