<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apache SkyWalking – BanyanDB</title>
    <link>/tags/banyandb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in BanyanDB on Apache SkyWalking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/tags/banyandb/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Apache SkyWalking 2025 in Review: Making BanyanDB Ready for Production</title>
      <link>/blog/2026-01-01-skywalking-2025-year-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2026-01-01-skywalking-2025-year-in-review/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;2025 was a very focused year for the Apache SkyWalking community: &lt;strong&gt;moving BanyanDB from “native storage” to a “production-ready default”&lt;/strong&gt;, and making SkyWalking APM fully benefit from that foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post summarizes the key milestones, with an emphasis on BanyanDB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;storage-strategy-saying-goodbye-to-h2&#34;&gt;Storage strategy: saying goodbye to H2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started 2025 with a clear direction: the &lt;strong&gt;H2 storage option is permanently removed&lt;/strong&gt;.
This change reduced long-term maintenance burden and removed a storage choice that was not aligned with production and cloud-native deployments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;banyandb-from-080-foundations-to-090-production-features&#34;&gt;BanyanDB: from 0.8.0 foundations to 0.9.0 production features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BanyanDB 0.8.0&lt;/strong&gt; delivered the “day-2 operations” foundation that a default storage backend needs. The community put a lot of effort into making queries faster and more predictable (for example &lt;code&gt;index_mode&lt;/code&gt;, numeric index types, and multiple query-path optimizations), while also making the system safer under real production pressure. Disk-usage thresholds and a query &lt;strong&gt;memory protector&lt;/strong&gt; were added as guardrails, and the operational toolbox matured with snapshot/backup/restore utilities and improved metadata synchronization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as importantly, 0.8.0 started filling in the missing pieces of a full platform: native property storage and lifecycle-related capabilities that later enabled stronger HA and stage-based deployment patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BanyanDB 0.9.0&lt;/strong&gt; was the “production features” milestone. It introduced the &lt;strong&gt;Trace&lt;/strong&gt; data model as a first-class citizen, which unlocked much deeper trace storage and query capabilities. On the reliability and scaling side, the release brought configurable replicas, liaison-side improvements (including load balancing and moving some TopN flow), and broader correctness work such as migrations, version compatibility checks, and access logs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also made long-term operations more cloud-friendly with backup/restore support for AWS S3, GCS, and Azure Blob Storage, and added authentication primitives needed in shared environments. In short, 0.9.0 is where BanyanDB clearly moved beyond a “fast storage engine” into a “production platform”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;skywalking-apm-banyandb-becomes-the-default-path&#34;&gt;SkyWalking APM: BanyanDB becomes the default path&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With &lt;strong&gt;APM 10.2.0&lt;/strong&gt;, the project made the strategic shift official: H2 was removed permanently, and BanyanDB 0.8.0 became the default path that SkyWalking invests in. A lot of the work here was not flashy, but essential — refining OAP behavior (group settings, index model changes, Progressive TTL, query limits, and more) so running BanyanDB in production felt stable and predictable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With &lt;strong&gt;APM 10.3.0&lt;/strong&gt;, SkyWalking and BanyanDB moved forward together: BanyanDB 0.9.0’s new trace model was adopted end-to-end, reducing inefficient query round-trips and enabling new query views that significantly lowered page latency. The integration also expanded into lifecycle-aware operations with hot/warm/cold stage configuration (including TTL and query support), and added BanyanDB &lt;strong&gt;self-monitoring&lt;/strong&gt; through OAP and the UI — the kind of end-to-end polish that turns a storage backend into a truly native solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’d like this review to cover &lt;strong&gt;APM 10.4.x&lt;/strong&gt; as well, please point me to the corresponding release content in this repo (I didn’t find an APM 10.4.0 release announcement in the current checkout).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;packaging-and-deployment-ecosystem-helm&#34;&gt;Packaging and deployment ecosystem (Helm)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BanyanDB’s production readiness is not only server features — it also depends on deployment maturity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helm charts:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SkyWalking Kubernetes Helm Chart 4.8.0 improved BanyanDB deployment defaults by updating the bundled BanyanDB Helm dependency, fixing an init-job volume-mount mismatch, and aligning OAP/UI images with the APM 10.3.0 line.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BanyanDB Helm 0.4.0 added backup/restore sidecars and a default volume for property storage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BanyanDB Helm 0.5.0 introduced stage-aware patterns (hot/warm/cold), improved lifecycle-sidecar scheduling, moved liaison to StatefulSet, refined internal networking, and expanded configuration options.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BanyanDB Helm 0.5.1 refined liaison configuration and fixed restore-init environment issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BanyanDB Helm 0.5.3 fixed a liaison/data-node port issue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-rest-of-the-community-agents-and-tooling-kept-moving&#34;&gt;The rest of the community: agents and tooling kept moving&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While storage was the “main storyline”, the community shipped releases across agents, clients, and surrounding components throughout 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is a consolidated view of the other releases, grouped by project, with the most important notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SkyWalking Java Agent&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9.4.0&lt;/strong&gt;: agent self-observability; async-profiler support; broader plugin improvements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9.5.0&lt;/strong&gt;: virtual thread executor plugin; compatibility and stability fixes; dependency upgrades.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SkyWalking Go&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0.6.0&lt;/strong&gt;: richer manual APIs (events/logs/metrics, set span error); goframev2 plugin; bug fixes including Redis cluster mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SkyWalking for NodeJS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0.8.0&lt;/strong&gt;: Express 4/5 compatibility, keep-alive HTTP trace fix, and test/dependency maintenance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SkyWalking Python&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.2.0&lt;/strong&gt;: sampling service, &lt;code&gt;sw_grpc&lt;/code&gt; plugin, async/profiling stability fixes, Python 3.13 support, and dropping Python 3.7.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SkyWalking PHP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.0.0&lt;/strong&gt;: reach 1.0; add PSR-3 log reporting; upgrade toolchain/dependencies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SkyWalking Rust&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0.9.0&lt;/strong&gt;: migrate to Rust edition 2024 and upgrade dependencies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0.10.0&lt;/strong&gt;: Kafka client configuration refactor, &lt;code&gt;rdkafka&lt;/code&gt; upgrade, CI maintenance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SkyWalking Ruby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0.1.0&lt;/strong&gt;: initialize agent core and e2e tests; add plugins for Sinatra, redis-rb, net-http, memcached, and Elasticsearch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SkyWalking Client JS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.0.0&lt;/strong&gt;: add Core Web Vitals and static resource metrics; fix fetch/resource error handling; dependency and e2e/test improvements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SkyWalking Satellite&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.3.0&lt;/strong&gt;: support native eBPF Access Log protocol and async-profiler protocol; upgrade Go toolchain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SkyWalking Eyes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0.7.0&lt;/strong&gt;: improve installation/docs, respect gitignore behavior, upgrade Go, and simplify release steps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0.8.0&lt;/strong&gt;: add Elixir support and stronger dependency-license scanning (notably Ruby via Gemfile.lock), plus stability fixes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;looking-ahead-possible-directions-in-2026&#34;&gt;Looking ahead: possible directions in 2026&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2025 was about making BanyanDB ready for production. In 2026, the community is exploring the next set of improvements that could make the whole stack simpler to operate, more stable under stress, and easier to integrate into broader observability ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Possible areas include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BanyanDB: remove the etcd dependency&lt;/strong&gt;: the direction under discussion is to move away from etcd (given ecosystem activity and maintenance concerns) and rely more on DNS-based discovery plus BanyanDB’s native property capabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BanyanDB: stronger stability testing&lt;/strong&gt;: more systematic testing, including chaos testing, to validate behavior under failures and noisy conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BanyanDB: better observability export&lt;/strong&gt;: introducing First Occurrence Data Collection (FODC) as a sidecar and proxy server to provide a unified stream of observability data to third-party systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SkyWalking APM: broader runtime and query capabilities&lt;/strong&gt;: cold-stage data query support, a newer Java runtime (Java 25), and consideration of TraceQL protocol (Temper) support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;closing&#34;&gt;Closing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who contributed to SkyWalking in 2025. Every contribution is high-value — code, documentation, reviews, testing, issue triage, and operational experience — and each of them helped move the project forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also want to say a special thank you to the countless end users across global companies. Many of the most valuable improvements don’t start from a pull request: they start from real-world use cases, performance investigations, production feedback, bug reports, and the patience to help us reproduce and validate fixes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As another milestone, SkyWalking reached &lt;strong&gt;968 GitHub contributors&lt;/strong&gt; globally, and we expect the &lt;strong&gt;1000th&lt;/strong&gt; contributor milestone to arrive soon in 2026. But the community is much larger than the number suggests, and SkyWalking’s progress has always been driven by collaboration between contributors, adopters, and maintainers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apache SkyWalking was originally created by Sheng Wu as a personal project in May 2015. It would never have grown into what it is today without the whole community — and it will keep moving forward because of the community.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zh: BanyanDB 0.6 版本发布：性能和效率的提升</title>
      <link>/zh/2024-06-04-banyandb-0.6-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh/2024-06-04-banyandb-0.6-release/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h1 id=&#34;引言&#34;&gt;引言&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们很高兴地宣布 BanyanDB v0.6 的发布，这是我们数据库技术发展的一个重要里程碑。这个最新版本引入了一种开创性的基于列的文件系统，提高了处理大数据集的性能和效率。经过广泛测试，我们可以确认这个新文件系统已经准备好投入生产。BanyanDB 现已准备就绪。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在这篇博客中，我们将深入探讨新的架构和观察到的性能改进，并提供一个关于如何安装并开始使用 BanyanDB v0.6 的逐步指南。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;理解-banyandb-架构&#34;&gt;理解 BanyanDB 架构&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BanyanDB 设计为一个高度可扩展的多模型数据库。BanyanDB 的架构是模块化的，允许在存储和索引策略上具有灵活性，这使其成为处理复杂数据环境的理想选择。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;主要特性&#34;&gt;主要特性：&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;多模型支持&lt;/strong&gt;：无缝处理各种数据类型。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;可扩展性&lt;/strong&gt;：设计为可以在多个节点上水平扩展。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;高性能&lt;/strong&gt;：优化了快速数据检索和高数据吞吐率。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;数据模型&#34;&gt;数据模型&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BanyanDB 是一个多模型数据库，旨在支持包括时间序列和键值数据在内的多种数据类型。这种灵活性对于需要多样化数据处理能力的现代 APM 系统至关重要。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;data_models.png&#34; alt=&#34;BanyanDB 模型&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BanyanDB 模型&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;时间序列数据&#34;&gt;时间序列数据：&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BanyanDB 管理时间序列数据，即按时间顺序索引的数据点，通常在等间隔的时间点记录。这使其理想用于离散时间数据的序列。在 BanyanDB 中，你可以通过两种结构存储时间序列数据：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stream&lt;/strong&gt;：这种类型的数据适合记录，如日志、追踪和事件。Stream（流）有助于管理连续生成并顺序记录的数据。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Measure&lt;/strong&gt;：专为摄取度量和概况而设计。Measure（度量）对于时间间隔的统计表示很有用。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;键值数据&#34;&gt;键值数据：&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BanyanDB 中的键值模型是属性模型的一个子集。每个属性由一个唯一的键标识，格式为&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;group&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;name&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;id&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;，作为检索数据的主键。这个键一旦设置就是不可改变，确保数据的一致性和完整性。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;属性由几个键值对组成，称为 Tag。你可以根据 Tag 的键动态地添加、更新或删除 Tag，提供灵活性在管理和存储数据方面。例如，SkyWalking UI 模板利用这个模型有效地存储配置数据。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;banyandb-的集群化&#34;&gt;BanyanDB 的集群化&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BanyanDB 的架构不仅确保了高效的数据管理和高可用性，还强调了其集群环境中的可扩展性。系统包括三种不同的节点类型，每种类型都能独立扩展以满足不同的工作负载需求。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;数据节点data-node&#34;&gt;数据节点（Data Node）&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;数据节点是存储和管理所有原始时间序列数据、元数据和索引数据的核心。这些节点采用无共享架构运行，彼此之间不直接通信也不共享任何数据，增强了集群的可用性并简化了维护和扩展。这种设计优先考虑可用性，即使某些节点暂时不可用，系统仍能保持数据摄取和查询操作。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;元数据节点meta-node&#34;&gt;元数据节点（Meta Node）&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;元数据节点使用 etcd 实现，管理整个集群的元数据并确保系统的一致性。它们维护节点状态和数据库架构的全局视图，促进集群内的协调操作。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;联络节点liaison-node&#34;&gt;联络节点（Liaison Node）&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;联络节点作为通信桥梁，将查询和数据路由到适当的数据节点。它们处理安全功能，如认证和 TTL 执行，并管理分布式查询执行以优化性能。它们在维护服务可用性中发挥关键作用；只要至少有一个数据节点在运行，联络节点就可以继续服务查询。在某些数据节点不可用的情况下，联络节点会将流量重定向到剩余的健康节点，这可能导致这些节点的资源使用增加。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;cluster.png&#34; alt=&#34;BanyanDB 集群&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BanyanDB 集群&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;通信&#34;&gt;通信&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;元数据节点&lt;/strong&gt; 在集群中同步元数据。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;数据节点&lt;/strong&gt; 与元数据节点互动，更新和获取元数据。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;联络节点&lt;/strong&gt; 将数据路由到数据节点并协调查询过程，利用元数据节点的元数据进行有效的分发和执行。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;可扩展性和容错性&#34;&gt;可扩展性和容错性&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BanyanDB 集群中的每种节点类型都可以根据部署的具体需要独立扩展：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;扩展数据节点&lt;/strong&gt; 增加数据处理能力并在更重的负载下改善性能。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;扩展元数据节点&lt;/strong&gt; 增强集群元数据操作的管理能力和弹性。这些节点的数量应该是奇数。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;扩展联络节点&lt;/strong&gt; 改善查询处理和数据路由能力的吞吐量。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这种灵活性使 BanyanDB 能够适应需求变化，而不会损害性能或可用性。如果某些组件暂时不可用，系统设计为继续运营，优先保证可用性而非严格一致性。然而，在这种事件中，如果活动节点没有足够的资源来处理当前的工作负载，用户可能会经历数据摄取和查询处理的延迟或失败。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;在-kubernetes-上安装&#34;&gt;在 Kubernetes 上安装&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;要在 Kubernetes 上安装 BanyanDB，你可以使用我们的 Helm chart，这简化了部署过程。你可以在&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apache/skywalking-helm/tree/v4.6.0&#34;&gt;我们的官方文档&lt;/a&gt;中找到详细的安装指南。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这个逐步指南假设你对 Kubernetes 和 Helm 有基本的了解，Helm 是 Kubernetes 的包管理器。如果你不熟悉 Helm，你可能需要在继续之前先熟悉 Helm 的基础知识。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;先决条件&#34;&gt;先决条件&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在我们开始之前，请确保你有以下内容：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kubernetes 集群&lt;/strong&gt;：你可以使用 Minikube 进行本地设置，或使用支持 Kubernetes 的任何云提供商，如 AWS、GCP 或 Azure。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Helm 3&lt;/strong&gt;：确保 Helm 3 已安装并配置在你的机器上。你可以从 &lt;a href=&#34;https://helm.sh/&#34;&gt;Helm 的官方网站&lt;/a&gt; 下载。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;第-1-步配置-helm-以使用-oci&#34;&gt;第 1 步：配置 Helm 以使用 OCI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;由于 BanyanDB Helm chart 托管为 Docker Hub 中的 OCI chart，你需要确保你的 Helm 配置为处理 OCI 工件。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#fff;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;helm registry login registry-1.docker.io
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;你将被提示输入你的 Docker Hub 用户名和密码。此步骤是从 Docker Hub 拉取 Helm chart 所必需的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;第-2-步设置环境变量&#34;&gt;第 2 步：设置环境变量&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;接下来，设置 SkyWalking 发行版本、名称和命名空间的环境变量。这些变量将用于后续命令。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#fff;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#0086b3&#34;&gt;export&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#008080&#34;&gt;SKYWALKING_RELEASE_VERSION&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;4.6.0
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#0086b3&#34;&gt;export&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#008080&#34;&gt;SKYWALKING_RELEASE_NAME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;skywalking
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#0086b3&#34;&gt;export&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#008080&#34;&gt;SKYWALKING_RELEASE_NAMESPACE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;default
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;第-3-步使用-helm-安装-banyandbskywalking&#34;&gt;第 3 步：使用 Helm 安装 BanyanDB+SkyWalking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#fff;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;helm install &lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;${&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#008080&#34;&gt;SKYWALKING_RELEASE_NAME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;\
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  oci://registry-1.docker.io/apache/skywalking-helm &lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;\
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  --version &lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;${&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#008080&#34;&gt;SKYWALKING_RELEASE_VERSION&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;\
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  -n &lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;${&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#008080&#34;&gt;SKYWALKING_RELEASE_NAMESPACE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;\
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  --set oap.image.tag&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;10.0.1 &lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;\
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  --set oap.storageType&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;banyandb &lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;\
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  --set ui.image.tag&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;10.0.1 &lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;\
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  --set elasticsearch.enabled&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#0086b3&#34;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;\
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  --set banyandb.enabled&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#0086b3&#34;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;\
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  --set banyandb.image.tag&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;0.6.1 &lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;\
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  --set banyandb.standalone.enabled&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#0086b3&#34;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;\
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  --set banyandb.cluster.enabled&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#0086b3&#34;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;\
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  --set banyandb.etcd.enabled&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#0086b3&#34;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;此命令将部署 SkyWalking OAP 集群和 BanyanDB 集群到你的 Kubernetes 环境。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;第-4-步验证安装&#34;&gt;第 4 步：验证安装&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;检查 pod 的状态以确保它们正常运行：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#fff;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;kubectl get pods -l &lt;span style=&#34;color:#008080&#34;&gt;release&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;skywalking
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;如果一切配置正确，你应该看到以下 pod 处于&lt;code&gt;Running&lt;/code&gt;或&lt;code&gt;Completed&lt;/code&gt;状态。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;pods.png&#34; alt=&#34;BanyanDB 集群中的 Pods&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BanyanDB 集群中的 Pod&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;第-5-步访问-skywalking-ui&#34;&gt;第 5 步：访问 SkyWalking UI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;要访问 SkyWalking UI，你可以检查服务：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#fff;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;kubectl get svc
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;你应该选择服务&lt;code&gt;skywalkin-skywalking-helm-ui&lt;/code&gt;来访问 UI。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;性能测试&#34;&gt;性能测试&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们针对 Elasticsearch 8.13.2 对 BanyanDB v0.6.1 进行了基准测试，SkyWalking 推荐的数据库。新的 BanyanDB 在几个关键领域表现优于 Elasticsearch，特别是在内存使用和磁盘空间方面。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;数据生成工具&#34;&gt;数据生成工具&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;对于此测试，我们使用了一个自定义的数据生成工具，设计用来创建模拟典型实际场景的追踪和度量数据。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;服务实例和端点&#34;&gt;服务、实例和端点&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Services&lt;/strong&gt;：20&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Groups of Services&lt;/strong&gt;：每 3 个生成器实例运行两组，贡献总服务数。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instances per Service&lt;/strong&gt;：每个服务有 20 个实例，所有服务共有 400 个实例。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Endpoints per Service&lt;/strong&gt;：每个服务实例托管 100 个端点。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Endpoints&lt;/strong&gt;：20 个服务的总端点数为 2000。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trace-和-segment-生成&#34;&gt;Trace 和 Segment 生成&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trace Gerneration Rate&lt;/strong&gt;：每组服务每秒生成 1000 条 trace，有效模拟大规模微服务环境中的高负载场景。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spans per Trace&lt;/strong&gt;：每条追踪包含五个 segement，详细描述了各种服务和实例之间的模拟交互。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Writes per Second&lt;/strong&gt;：2 group * 3 data-generator * 1000 trace * 5 segment = 30k segment。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们设计的额外查询类型代表了生产环境中监控微服务架构的 SkyWalking 执行的典型读取操作。每种查询类型针对服务数据的不同方面：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1service-dashboard-queries&#34;&gt;1. &lt;strong&gt;Service Dashboard Queries&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;目的&lt;/strong&gt;：在过去 30 分钟内获取 5 项服务级别的度量。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;频率&lt;/strong&gt;：每秒 1 次查询&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2top-n-list-queries&#34;&gt;2. &lt;strong&gt;Top-N List Queries&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;目的&lt;/strong&gt;：在过去 30 分钟内检索 2 个特定服务的前 5 项度量。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;频率&lt;/strong&gt;：每秒 1 次查询。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3segment-list-queries&#34;&gt;3. &lt;strong&gt;Segment List Queries&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;目的&lt;/strong&gt;：在过去 30 分钟内获取按降序排列的服务段列表。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;频率&lt;/strong&gt;：每秒 1 次查询。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;4trace-detail-queries&#34;&gt;4. &lt;strong&gt;Trace Detail Queries&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;目的&lt;/strong&gt;：从段列表检索所有追踪细节。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;频率&lt;/strong&gt;：每秒 2 次查询。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;设置&#34;&gt;设置&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;下表详细列出了集群内每个组件的规格，允许轻松比较分配给每个系统的硬件资源。这提供了对 Elasticsearch 8.13.2 和我们性能测试中使用的 BanyanDB v0.6.1 部署配置的清晰而结构化的比较。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;test_setup.png&#34; alt=&#34;性能测试设置&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;性能测试设置&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;集群配置表&#34;&gt;集群配置表&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;组件&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;系统&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;数量&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;CPU 核心&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;内存 (GB)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;存储 (GB)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;角色描述&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;主节点&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Elasticsearch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;集群协调和管理&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;数据节点&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Elasticsearch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50 (高级 RWO)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;数据存储、索引和查询处理&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ETCD 节点&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BanyanDB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;元数据和集群状态存储&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;数据节点&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BanyanDB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50 (高级 RWO)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;数据存储和处理&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;联络节点&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BanyanDB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;协调客户端应用和数据节点间的联系&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;结果&#34;&gt;结果&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在此我们整理了 Elasticsearch 8.13.2 和 BanyanDB v0.6.1 的性能测试结果，重点比较资源使用情况。结果分为两个表格以便更清晰地展示——一个详细介绍 CPU 和内存使用情况，另一个关注磁盘相关指标。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cpu-和内存使用情况&#34;&gt;CPU 和内存使用情况&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;cpu.png&#34; alt=&#34;CPU&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;memory.png&#34; alt=&#34;内存&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;系统&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;平均 CPU 使用率 (核心)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;平均内存使用量 (MB)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Elasticsearch 数据&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4147&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BanyanDB 数据&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;738&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BanyanDB 联络&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;62&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;观察&#34;&gt;观察：&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CPU 使用率&lt;/strong&gt;：BanyanDB 数据节点的 CPU 使用率略高，因为它们在压缩和解压数据文件时操作较多。然而，BanyanDB 联络节点的 CPU 使用明显较少。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;内存使用率&lt;/strong&gt;：BanyanDB 显示出显著较低的内存使用率，数据和联络节点的内存使用量几乎比 Elasticsearch 数据节点少 5 倍，凸显其在内存利用效率方面的优势。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;磁盘使用iops-和吞吐量&#34;&gt;磁盘使用、IOPS 和吞吐量&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;disk_usage.png&#34; alt=&#34;磁盘使用&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;磁盘使用&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;disk_iops.png&#34; alt=&#34;磁盘 IOPS&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;disk_throughput.png&#34; alt=&#34;磁盘吞吐量&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;磁盘 IOPS &amp;amp; 吞吐量&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;系统&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;平均磁盘使用量 (GB)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;IOPS (千)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;磁盘吞吐量 (GB/s)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Elasticsearch 数据&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;29.6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;115.5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BanyanDB 数据&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;21.6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;21.4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;观察-1&#34;&gt;观察：&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;磁盘空间使用&lt;/strong&gt;：BanyanDB 比 Elasticsearch 使用约 30% 较少的磁盘空间，这可能导致较低的存储成本。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IOPS 和吞吐量&lt;/strong&gt;：BanyanDB 的 IOPS 和磁盘吞吐量显著较低，表明对磁盘资源的压力较小。这对于降低运营成本和延长物理存储设备的使用寿命可能是有益的。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;结论&#34;&gt;结论&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BanyanDB v0.6 的发布标志着数据库技术的重大进步，其新的基于列的文件系统在性能和效率上，尤其是在内存使用和磁盘空间方面与 Elasticsearch 相比显示出显著的改进。BanyanDB 能够处理各种数据类型，具有可扩展的架构以及在数据检索和摄取方面的高性能，使其成为复杂数据环境的强大解决方案。灵活的集群系统的引入允许独立扩展节点类型，确保在不影响性能或可用性的情况下适应变化的需求。总体而言，BanyanDB v0.6 将自己定位为现代应用性能管理 (APM) 系统的一个经济高效且可靠的选择。&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: BanyanDB 0.6 Release: Enhanced Performance and Efficiency</title>
      <link>/blog/2024-06-04-banyandb-0.6-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2024-06-04-banyandb-0.6-release/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce the release of BanyanDB v0.6, a significant milestone in the evolution of our database technology. This latest version introduces a groundbreaking column-based file system that enhances performance and improves efficiency in handling large datasets. After extensive testing, we can confirm that this new file system is ready for production. BanyanDB is now production-ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, we’ll dive deep into the new architecture and the performance improvements observed and provide a step-by-step guide on installing and getting started with BanyanDB v0.6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;understanding-banyandb-architecture&#34;&gt;Understanding BanyanDB Architecture&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BanyanDB is designed as a highly scalable, multi-model database. The architecture of BanyanDB is modular, allowing for flexibility in storage and indexing strategies, which makes it an ideal choice for complex data environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-features&#34;&gt;Key Features:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-Model Support:&lt;/strong&gt; Seamlessly handles various data types.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scalability:&lt;/strong&gt; Designed to scale horizontally across multiple nodes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High Performance:&lt;/strong&gt; Optimized for quick data retrieval and high data ingestion rates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-model&#34;&gt;Data Model&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BanyanDB is a multi-model database engineered to support diverse data types, including time series and key-value data. This flexibility is essential for modern APM systems that require versatile data handling capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;data_models.png&#34; alt=&#34;BanyanDB Models&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BanyanDB Models&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;time-series-data&#34;&gt;Time-Series Data:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BanyanDB manages time-series data, which are data points indexed in time order, typically logged at successive, equally spaced points in time. This makes it ideal for a sequence of discrete-time data. In BanyanDB, you can store time-series data through two structures:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stream&lt;/strong&gt;: This type of data is suitable for logging, such as logs, traces, and events. Streams help manage data that are continuously generated and sequentially recorded.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Measure&lt;/strong&gt;: Designed for ingesting metrics and profiles. Measures are useful for statistical representations over intervals of time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-value-data&#34;&gt;Key-Value Data:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key-value model in BanyanDB is a subset of the Property model. Each property is identified by a unique key formatted as &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;group&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;name&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;id&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, which acts as a primary key for retrieving data. This key is immutable once set, ensuring data consistency and integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Properties consist of several key-value pairs, referred to as Tags. You can dynamically add, update, or drop tags based on the tag&amp;rsquo;s key, offering flexibility in managing and storing data. For example, SkyWalking UI templates utilize this model to store configuration data efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;clustering-in-banyandb&#34;&gt;Clustering in BanyanDB&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BanyanDB&amp;rsquo;s architecture not only ensures efficient data management and high availability but also emphasizes scalability across its clustered environment. The system includes three distinct node types, each capable of scaling independently to meet varying workload demands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-nodes&#34;&gt;Data Nodes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data Nodes are central to storing and managing all raw time series data, metadata, and indexed data. Operating under a shared-nothing architecture, these nodes do not communicate directly with each other nor share any data, enhancing cluster availability and simplifying maintenance and scaling. This design prioritizes availability, allowing the system to remain operational for data ingestion and querying even if some nodes are temporarily unavailable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;meta-nodes&#34;&gt;Meta Nodes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implemented using etcd, Meta Nodes manage the overarching cluster metadata and ensure consistency across the system. They maintain a global view of the node states and database schemas, facilitating coordinated operations within the cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;liaison-nodes&#34;&gt;Liaison Nodes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liaison Nodes serve as the communication bridge, routing queries and data to the appropriate Data Nodes. They handle security functions like authentication and TTL enforcement, and manage distributed query execution to optimize performance. They play a crucial role in maintaining service availability; as long as at least one Data Node is operational, Liaison Nodes can continue to serve queries. In scenarios where some Data Nodes are unavailable, Liaison Nodes reroute traffic to the remaining healthy nodes, which may lead to increased resource use on these nodes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;cluster.png&#34; alt=&#34;BanyanDB Cluster&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BanyanDB Cluster&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;communication&#34;&gt;Communication&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meta Nodes&lt;/strong&gt; synchronize metadata across the cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Nodes&lt;/strong&gt; interact with Meta Nodes to update and fetch metadata.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Liaison Nodes&lt;/strong&gt; route data to Data Nodes and coordinate query processes, leveraging metadata from Meta Nodes for efficient distribution and execution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scalability-and-fault-tolerance&#34;&gt;Scalability and Fault Tolerance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each node type within the BanyanDB cluster can be scaled independently based on the specific needs of the deployment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scaling Data Nodes&lt;/strong&gt; increases data handling capacity and improves performance under heavier loads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scaling Meta Nodes&lt;/strong&gt; enhances the management capabilities and resiliency of cluster metadata operations. The number of such nodes should be odd.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scaling Liaison Nodes&lt;/strong&gt; improves the throughput of query processing and data routing capabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This flexibility allows BanyanDB to adapt to changes in demand without compromising performance or availability. If some components become temporarily unavailable, the system is designed to continue operations, prioritizing availability over strict consistency. However, during such events, if the active nodes do not have sufficient resources to handle the current workload, users may experience delays or failures in data ingestion and query processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;installation-on-kubernetes&#34;&gt;Installation On Kubernetes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To install BanyanDB on Kubernetes, you can use our Helm chart, which simplifies the deployment process.  You can find detailed installation instructions in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apache/skywalking-helm/tree/v4.6.0&#34;&gt;our official documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This step-by-step guide assumes you have a basic understanding of Kubernetes and Helm, the package manager for Kubernetes. If you&amp;rsquo;re new to Helm, you might want to familiarize yourself with Helm basics before proceeding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we begin, ensure you have the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Kubernetes Cluster&lt;/strong&gt;: You can use Minikube for a local setup, or any cloud provider like AWS, GCP, or Azure that supports Kubernetes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Helm 3&lt;/strong&gt;: Ensure Helm 3 is installed and configured on your machine. You can download it from &lt;a href=&#34;https://helm.sh/&#34;&gt;Helm&amp;rsquo;s official website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-configure-helm-to-use-oci&#34;&gt;Step 1: Configure Helm to Use OCI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the BanyanDB Helm chart is hosted as an OCI chart in Docker Hub, you need to ensure your Helm is configured to handle OCI artifacts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#fff;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;helm registry login registry-1.docker.io
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;You will be prompted to enter your Docker Hub username and password. This step is necessary to pull Helm charts from Docker Hub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-2-setup-env-variables&#34;&gt;Step 2: Setup Env Variables&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, set up the environment variables for the SkyWalking release version, name, and namespace. These variables will be used in subsequent commands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#fff;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#0086b3&#34;&gt;export&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#008080&#34;&gt;SKYWALKING_RELEASE_VERSION&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;4.6.0
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#0086b3&#34;&gt;export&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#008080&#34;&gt;SKYWALKING_RELEASE_NAME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;skywalking
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#0086b3&#34;&gt;export&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#008080&#34;&gt;SKYWALKING_RELEASE_NAMESPACE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;default
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-3-install-banyandbskywalking-using-helm&#34;&gt;Step 3: Install BanyanDB+SkyWalking Using Helm&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#fff;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;helm install &lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;${&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#008080&#34;&gt;SKYWALKING_RELEASE_NAME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;\
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  oci://registry-1.docker.io/apache/skywalking-helm &lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;\
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  --version &lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;${&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#008080&#34;&gt;SKYWALKING_RELEASE_VERSION&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;\
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  -n &lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;${&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#008080&#34;&gt;SKYWALKING_RELEASE_NAMESPACE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;\
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  --set oap.image.tag&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;10.0.1 &lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;\
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  --set oap.storageType&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;banyandb &lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;\
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  --set ui.image.tag&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;10.0.1 &lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;\
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  --set elasticsearch.enabled&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#0086b3&#34;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;\
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  --set banyandb.enabled&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#0086b3&#34;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;\
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  --set banyandb.image.tag&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;0.6.1 &lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;\
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  --set banyandb.standalone.enabled&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#0086b3&#34;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;\
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  --set banyandb.cluster.enabled&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#0086b3&#34;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;\
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d14&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  --set banyandb.etcd.enabled&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#0086b3&#34;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This command will deploy the SkyWalking OAP cluster and BanyanDB cluster to your Kubernetes environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-4-verify-the-installation&#34;&gt;Step 4: Verify the Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check the status of the pods to ensure they are running properly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#fff;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;kubectl get pods -l &lt;span style=&#34;color:#008080&#34;&gt;release&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;skywalking
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;You should see the following pods in a &lt;code&gt;Running&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Completed&lt;/code&gt; state if everything is configured correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;pods.png&#34; alt=&#34;Pods in BanyanDB Cluster&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pods in BanyanDB Cluster&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-5-access-skywalking-ui&#34;&gt;Step 5: Access SkyWalking UI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To access the SkyWalking UI, you can check the service by :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#fff;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;kubectl get svc
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;You should select the service &lt;code&gt;skywalkin-skywalking-helm-ui&lt;/code&gt; to access the UI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;performance-test&#34;&gt;Performance Test&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We benchmarked BanyanDB v0.6.1 against Elasticsearch 8.13.2, SkyWalking’s recommended database. The new BanyanDB outperformed Elasticsearch in several key areas, particularly in memory usage and disk space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-generation-tool&#34;&gt;Data Generation Tool&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this test, we used a custom data generation tool designed to create data that mimics a typical real-world scenario for trace and metrics data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;services-instances-and-endpoints&#34;&gt;Services, Instances, and Endpoints&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Services:&lt;/strong&gt; 20&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Groups of Services:&lt;/strong&gt; Each of the 3 generator instances runs two groups, contributing to the total count of services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instances per Service:&lt;/strong&gt; Each service is represented by 20 instances, leading to 400 instances across all services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Endpoints per Service:&lt;/strong&gt; Each service instance hosts 100 endpoints.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Endpoints:&lt;/strong&gt; With 20 services, the total number of endpoints is 2000.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trace-and-segment-generation&#34;&gt;Trace and Segment Generation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trace Generation Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; Each group of services generates 1000 traces per second, effectively simulating a high-load scenario typical in large-scale microservice environments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spans per Trace:&lt;/strong&gt; Each trace comprises five segments, detailing the simulated interactions between various services and instances.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total Writes per Second: 2 groups * 3 data-generators * 1000 traces * 5 segments = 30k segments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The additional query types were designed to represent typical read operations performed in a production environment monitoring microservice architectures by SkyWalking. Each query type targets a different aspect of service data:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1service-dashboard-queries&#34;&gt;1. &lt;strong&gt;Service Dashboard Queries&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose:&lt;/strong&gt; Fetch 5 service-level metrics over the last 30 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frequency:&lt;/strong&gt; 1 query per second&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2top-n-list-queries&#34;&gt;2. &lt;strong&gt;Top-N List Queries&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose:&lt;/strong&gt; Retrieve the top 5 metrics for 2 specific services over the last 30 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frequency:&lt;/strong&gt; 1 query per second.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3segment-list-queries&#34;&gt;3. &lt;strong&gt;Segment List Queries&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose:&lt;/strong&gt; Fetch a list of service segments ordered by descending latency within the last 30 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frequency:&lt;/strong&gt; 1 query per second.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;4trace-detail-queries&#34;&gt;4. &lt;strong&gt;Trace Detail Queries&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose:&lt;/strong&gt; Retrieve all trace details from the segment list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frequency:&lt;/strong&gt; 2 queries per second.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;setup&#34;&gt;Setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is a detailed table that outlines the specifications of each component within the clusters, allowing for an easy comparison of hardware resources allocated to each system. This provides a clear and structured comparison of the deployment configurations used for Elasticsearch 8.13.2 and BanyanDB v0.6.1 in our performance tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;test_setup.png&#34; alt=&#34;Performance Test Setup&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Performance Test Setup&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cluster-configuration-table&#34;&gt;Cluster Configuration Table&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Component&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;System&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Quantity&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;CPU Cores&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;RAM (GB)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Storage (GB)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Role Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Master Nodes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Elasticsearch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Cluster coordination and management&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Data Nodes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Elasticsearch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50 (Premium RWO)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Data storage, indexing, and query processing&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ETCD Nodes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BanyanDB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Metadata and cluster state storage&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Data Nodes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BanyanDB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50 (Premium RWO)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Data storage and processing&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Liaison Nodes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BanyanDB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Coordination between client applications and data nodes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;result&#34;&gt;Result&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we consolidate the performance test results for Elasticsearch 8.13.2 and BanyanDB v0.6.1, focusing on resource usage comparisons. The results are organized into two tables for better clarity—one detailing CPU and memory usage, and the other focusing on disk-related metrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cpu-and-memory-usage&#34;&gt;CPU and Memory Usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;cpu.png&#34; alt=&#34;CPU&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;memory.png&#34; alt=&#34;Memory&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;System&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Mean CPU Usage (cores)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Mean Memory Usage (MB)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Elasticsearch Data&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4147&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BanyanDB Data&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;738&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BanyanDB Liaison&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;62&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;observations&#34;&gt;Observations:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CPU Usage:&lt;/strong&gt; BanyanDB data nodes have slightly higher CPU usage due to their operations on compressing and decompressing data files. However, BanyanDB liaison nodes use significantly less CPU.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Memory Usage:&lt;/strong&gt; BanyanDB shows markedly lower memory usage for both data and liaison nodes, using nearly 5x less memory than Elasticsearch data nodes, highlighting its efficiency in memory utilization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;disk-usage-iops-and-throughput&#34;&gt;Disk Usage, IOPS, and Throughput&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;disk_usage.png&#34; alt=&#34;Disk Usage&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disk Usage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;disk_iops.png&#34; alt=&#34;Disk IOPS&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;disk_throughput.png&#34; alt=&#34;Disk Throughput&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disk IOPS &amp;amp; Throughput&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;System&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Mean Disk Usage (GB)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;IOPS (k)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Disk Throughput (GB/s)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Elasticsearch Data&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;29.6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;115.5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BanyanDB Data&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;21.6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;21.4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;observations-1&#34;&gt;Observations:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disk Space Usage:&lt;/strong&gt; BanyanDB utilizes about 30% less disk space than Elasticsearch, which can translate into lower storage costs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IOPS and Throughput:&lt;/strong&gt; BanyanDB&amp;rsquo;s IOPS and disk throughput are significantly lower, indicating less strain on disk resources. This could be beneficial for reducing operational costs and extending the lifespan of physical storage devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The release of BanyanDB v0.6 marks a significant advancement in database technology with its new column-based file system. This version demonstrates substantial improvements in both performance and efficiency, particularly in memory usage and disk space compared to Elasticsearch. BanyanDB&amp;rsquo;s ability to handle various data types, its scalable architecture, and its high performance in data retrieval and ingestion make it a robust solution for complex data environments. The introduction of a flexible clustering system allows for independent scaling of node types, ensuring adaptability to changing demands without compromising on performance or availability. Overall, BanyanDB v0.6 positions itself as a cost-effective and reliable choice for modern application performance management (APM) systems.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: SkyWalking 10 Release: Service Hierarchy, Kubernetes Network Monitoring by eBPF, BanyanDB, and More</title>
      <link>/blog/2024-05-13-skywalking-10-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2024-05-13-skywalking-10-release/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The Apache SkyWalking team today announced the 10 release. SkyWalking 10 provides a host of groundbreaking features and enhancements.
The introduction of Layer and Service Hierarchy streamlines monitoring by organizing services and metrics into distinct layers and providing seamless navigation across them.
Leveraging eBPF technology, Kubernetes Network Monitoring delivers granular insights into network traffic, topology, and TCP/HTTP metrics.
BanyanDB emerges as a high-performance native storage solution, while expanded monitoring support encompasses Apache RocketMQ, ClickHouse,
and Apache ActiveMQ Classic. Support for Multiple Labels Names enhances flexibility in metrics analysis,
while enhanced exporting and querying capabilities streamline data dissemination and processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release blog briefly introduces these new features and enhancements as well as some other notable changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;layer-and-service-hierarchy&#34;&gt;Layer and Service Hierarchy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Layer&lt;/code&gt; concept was introduced in SkyWalking 9.0.0, it represents an abstract framework in computer science,
such as Operating System(OS_LINUX layer), Kubernetes(k8s layer). It organizes services and metrics into different layers based on their roles
and responsibilities in the system. SkyWalking provides a suite of monitoring and diagnostic tools for each layer, but there is a gap between the layers,
which can not easily bridge the data across different layers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In SkyWalking 10, SkyWalking provides new abilities to jump/connect across different layers and provide a seamless monitoring experience for users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;layer-jump&#34;&gt;Layer Jump&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the topology graph, users can click on a service node to jump to the dashboard of the service in another layer.
The following figures show the jump from the &lt;code&gt;GENERAL&lt;/code&gt; layer service topology to the &lt;code&gt;VIRTUAL_DATABASE&lt;/code&gt; service layer dashboard by clicking the topology node.
&lt;img src=&#34;layer_jump.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Figure 1: Layer Jump&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: Layer Jump&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;layer_jump2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Figure 2: Layer jump Dashboard&#34;&gt;
Figure 2: Layer jump Dashboard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;service-hierarchy&#34;&gt;Service Hierarchy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SkyWalking 10 introduces a new concept called &lt;code&gt;Service Hierarchy&lt;/code&gt;, which defines the relationships of existing logically same services in various layers.
OAP will detect the services from different layers, and try to build the connections.
Users can click the &lt;code&gt;Hierarchy Services&lt;/code&gt; in any layer&amp;rsquo;s service topology node or service dashboard to get the &lt;code&gt;Hierarchy Topology&lt;/code&gt;.
In this topology graph, users can see the relationships between the services in different layers and the summary of the metrics and also can jump to the service dashboard in the layer.
When a service occurs performance issue, users can easily analyze the metrics from different layers and track down the root cause:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The examples of the &lt;code&gt;Service Hierarchy&lt;/code&gt; relationships:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The application &lt;code&gt;song&lt;/code&gt; deployed in the Kubernetes cluster with SkyWalking agent and Service Mesh at the same time.
So the application &lt;code&gt;song&lt;/code&gt; across the &lt;code&gt;GENERAL&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;MESH&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;MESH_DP&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;K8S_SERVICE&lt;/code&gt; layers which could be monitored by SkyWalking,
the &lt;code&gt;Service Hierarchy&lt;/code&gt; topology as below:
&lt;img src=&#34;song.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Figure 3: Service Hierarchy Agent With K8s Service And Mesh With K8s Service&#34;&gt;
Figure 3: Service Hierarchy Agent With K8s Service And Mesh With K8s Service.&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
And can also have the &lt;code&gt;Service Instance Hierarchy&lt;/code&gt; topology to get the single instance status across the layers as below:
&lt;img src=&#34;song_instance.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Figure 4: Instance Hierarchy Agent With K8s Service(Pod)&#34;&gt;
Figure 4: Instance Hierarchy Agent With K8s Service(Pod)&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The PostgreSQL database &lt;code&gt;psql&lt;/code&gt; deployed in the Kubernetes cluster and used by the application &lt;code&gt;song&lt;/code&gt;.
So the database &lt;code&gt;psql&lt;/code&gt; across the &lt;code&gt;VIRTUAL_DATABASE&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;POSTGRESQL&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;K8S_SERVICE&lt;/code&gt; layers which could be monitored by SkyWalking,
the &lt;code&gt;Service Hierarchy&lt;/code&gt; topology as below:
&lt;img src=&#34;postgre.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Figure 5: Service Hierarchy Agent(Virtual Database) With Real Database And K8s Service&#34;&gt;
Figure 5: Service Hierarchy Agent(Virtual Database) With Real Database And K8s Service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more supported layers and how to detect the relationships between services in different layers please refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://skywalking.apache.org/docs/main/latest/en/concepts-and-designs/service-hierarchy/#service-hierarchy&#34;&gt;Service Hierarchy&lt;/a&gt;.
how to configure the &lt;code&gt;Service Hierarchy&lt;/code&gt; in SkyWalking, please refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://skywalking.apache.org/docs/main/latest/en/concepts-and-designs/service-hierarchy-configuration/&#34;&gt;Service Hierarchy Configuration&lt;/a&gt; section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;monitoring-kubernetes-network-traffic-by-using-ebpf&#34;&gt;Monitoring Kubernetes Network Traffic by using eBPF&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the previous version, skyWalking provides &lt;a href=&#34;https://skywalking.apache.org/docs/main/latest/en/setup/backend/backend-k8s-monitoring-metrics-cadvisor/&#34;&gt;Kubernetes (K8s) monitoring from kube-state-metrics and cAdvisor&lt;/a&gt;,
which can monitor the Kubernetes cluster status and the metrics of the Kubernetes resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In SkyWalking 10, by leverage &lt;a href=&#34;https://skywalking.apache.org/docs/skywalking-rover/latest/readme/&#34;&gt;Apache SkyWalking Rover&lt;/a&gt; 0.6+,
SkyWalking has the ability to monitor the Kubernetes network traffic by using eBPF, which can collect and map access logs from applications in Kubernetes environments.
Through these data, SkyWalking can analyze and provide the Service Traffic, Topology, TCP/HTTP level metrics from the Kubernetes aspect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following figures show the Topology and TCP Dashboard of the Kubernetes network traffic:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;k8s_topology.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Figure 6: Kubernetes Network Traffic Topology&#34;&gt;
Figure 6: Kubernetes Network Traffic Topology&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;k8s_dashboard.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Figure 7: Kubernetes Network Traffic TCP Dashboard&#34;&gt;
Figure 7: Kubernetes Network Traffic TCP Dashboard&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More details about how to monitor the Kubernetes network traffic by using eBPF, please refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://skywalking.apache.org/blog/2024-03-18-monitor-kubernetes-network-by-ebpf/&#34;&gt;Monitoring Kubernetes Network Traffic by using eBPF&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;banyandb---native-apm-database&#34;&gt;BanyanDB - Native APM Database&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://skywalking.apache.org/docs/skywalking-banyandb/latest/readme/&#34;&gt;BanyanDB&lt;/a&gt; 0.6.0 and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apache/skywalking-banyandb-java-client&#34;&gt;BanyanDB Java client&lt;/a&gt; 0.6.0 are released with SkyWalking 10,
As a native storage solution for SkyWalking, BanyanDB is going to be SkyWalking&amp;rsquo;s next-generation storage solution. This is recommended to use for medium-scale deployments from 0.6 until 1.0.&lt;br&gt;
It has shown high potential performance improvement. Less than 50% CPU usage and 50% memory usage with 40% disk volume compared to Elasticsearch in the same scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;apache-rocketmq-server-monitoring&#34;&gt;Apache RocketMQ Server Monitoring&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apache RocketMQ is an open-source distributed messaging and streaming platform, which is widely used in various scenarios including Internet, big data, mobile Internet, IoT, and other fields.
SkyWalking provides a basic monitoring dashboard for RocketMQ, which includes the following metrics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cluster Metrics: including messages produced/consumed today, total producer/consumer TPS, producer/consumer message size, messages produced/consumed until yesterday, max consumer latency, max commitLog disk ratio, commitLog disk ratio, pull/send threadPool queue head wait time, topic count, and broker count.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Broker Metrics: including produce/consume TPS, producer/consumer message size.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Topic Metrics: including max producer/consumer message size, consumer latency, producer/consumer TPS, producer/consumer offset, producer/consumer message size, consumer group count, and broker count.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following figure shows the RocketMQ Cluster Metrics dashboard:
&lt;img src=&#34;rocket_mq.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Figure 8: Apache RocketMQ Server Monitoring&#34;&gt;
Figure 8: Apache RocketMQ Server Monitoring&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more metrics and details about the RocketMQ monitoring, please refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://skywalking.apache.org/docs/main/latest/en/setup/backend/backend-rocketmq-monitoring/&#34;&gt;Apache RocketMQ Server Monitoring&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;clickhouse-server-monitoring&#34;&gt;ClickHouse Server Monitoring&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ClickHouse is an open-source column-oriented database management system that allows generating analytical data reports in real-time, it is widely used for online analytical processing (OLAP).
ClickHouse monitoring provides monitoring of the metrics 、events and asynchronous metrics of the ClickHouse server, which includes the following parts of metrics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Server Metrics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Query Metrics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Network Metrics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Insert Metrics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replica Metrics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MergeTree Metrics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ZooKeeper Metrics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Embedded ClickHouse Keeper Metrics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following figure shows the ClickHouse Cluster Metrics dashboard:
&lt;img src=&#34;clickhouse.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Figure 9: ClickHouse Server Monitoring&#34;&gt;
Figure 9: ClickHouse Server Monitoring&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more metrics and details about the ClickHouse monitoring, please refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://skywalking.apache.org/docs/main/latest/en/setup/backend/backend-clickhouse-monitoring/&#34;&gt;ClickHouse Server Monitoring&lt;/a&gt;,
and here is a blog that can help for a quick start &lt;a href=&#34;https://skywalking.apache.org/blog/2024-03-12-monitoring-clickhouse-through-skywalking/&#34;&gt;Monitoring ClickHouse through SkyWalking&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;apache-activemq-server-monitoring&#34;&gt;Apache ActiveMQ Server Monitoring&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apache ActiveMQ Classic is a popular and powerful open-source messaging and integration pattern server.
SkyWalking provides a basic monitoring dashboard for ActiveMQ, which includes the following metrics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cluster Metrics: including memory usage, rates of write/read, and average/max duration of write.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Broker Metrics: including node state, number of connections, number of producers/consumers, and rate of write/read under the broker. Depending on the cluster mode, one cluster may include one or more brokers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Destination Metrics: including number of producers/consumers, messages in different states, queues, and enqueue duration in a queue/topic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following figure shows the ActiveMQ Cluster Metrics dashboard:
&lt;img src=&#34;active_mq.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Figure 10: Apache ActiveMQ Server Monitoring&#34;&gt;
Figure 10: Apache ActiveMQ Server Monitoring&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more metrics and details about the ActiveMQ monitoring, please refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://skywalking.apache.org/docs/main/latest/en/setup/backend/backend-activemq-monitoring/&#34;&gt;Apache ActiveMQ Server Monitoring&lt;/a&gt;,
and here is a blog that can help for a quick start &lt;a href=&#34;https://skywalking.apache.org/blog/2024-04-19-monitoring-activemq-through-skywalking/&#34;&gt;Monitoring ActiveMQ through SkyWalking&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;support-multiple-labels-names&#34;&gt;Support Multiple Labels Names&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before SkyWalking 10, SkyWalking does not store the labels names in the metrics data, which makes MQE have to use &lt;code&gt;_&lt;/code&gt; as the generic label name,
it can&amp;rsquo;t query the metrics data with multiple labels names.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SkyWalking 10 supports storing the labels names in the metrics data, and MQE can query or calculate the metrics data with multiple labels names.
For example:
The &lt;code&gt;k8s_cluster_deployment_status&lt;/code&gt; metric has labels &lt;code&gt;namespace&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;deployment&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;status&lt;/code&gt;.
If we want to query all deployment metric values with &lt;code&gt;namespace=skywalking-showcase&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;status=true&lt;/code&gt;, we can use the following expression:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#fff;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34; data-lang=&#34;text&#34;&gt;k8s_cluster_deployment_status{namespace=&amp;#39;skywalking-showcase&amp;#39;, status=&amp;#39;true&amp;#39;}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;related enhancement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since Alarm rule configuration had migrated to the MQE in SkyWalking 9.6.0, the alarm rule also supports multiple labels names.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PromeQL service supports multiple labels names query.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;metrics-grpc-exporter&#34;&gt;Metrics gRPC exporter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SkyWalking 10 enhanced the &lt;a href=&#34;https://skywalking.apache.org/docs/main/latest/en/setup/backend/exporter/#grpc-exporter&#34;&gt;metrics gPRC exporter&lt;/a&gt;,
it supports exporting all types of metrics data to the gRPC server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;skywalking-native-ui-metrics-query-switch-to-v3-apis&#34;&gt;SkyWalking Native UI Metrics Query Switch to V3 APIs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SkyWalking Native UI metrics query deprecate the V2 APIs, and all migrated to &lt;a href=&#34;https://skywalking.apache.org/docs/main/latest/en/api/query-protocol/#v3-apis&#34;&gt;V3 APIs&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href=&#34;https://skywalking.apache.org/docs/main/next/en/api/metrics-query-expression/#metrics-query-expressionmqe-syntax&#34;&gt;MQE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-notable-enhancements&#34;&gt;Other Notable Enhancements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support Java 21 runtime and oap-java21 image for Java 21 runtime.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove CLI(&lt;code&gt;swctl&lt;/code&gt;) from the image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More MQE functions and operators supported.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhance the native UI and improve the user experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Several bugs and CVEs fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zh: SkyWalking 10 发布：服务层次结构、基于 eBPF 的 Kubernetes 网络监控、BanyanDB 等</title>
      <link>/zh/2024-05-13-skywalking-10-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh/2024-05-13-skywalking-10-release/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Apache SkyWalking 团队今天宣布发布 SkyWalking 10。SkyWalking 10 提供了一系列突破性的功能和增强功能。Layer 和 Service Hierarchy 的引入通过将服务和指标组织成不同的层次，并提供跨层无缝导航，从而简化了监控。利用 eBPF 技术，Kubernetes 网络监控提供了对网络流量、拓扑和 TCP/HTTP 指标的详细洞察。BanyanDB 作为高性能的原生存储解决方案出现，同时扩展的监控支持包括 Apache RocketMQ、ClickHouse 和 Apache ActiveMQ Classic。对多标签名称的支持增强了指标分析的灵活性，而增强的导出和查询功能简化了数据分发和处理。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;本文简要介绍了这些新功能和增强功能以及其他一些值得注意的变化。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;layer-和-service-hierarchy&#34;&gt;Layer 和 Service Hierarchy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Layer 概念是在 SkyWalking 9.0.0 中引入的，它代表计算机科学中的一个抽象框架，例如操作系统（OS_LINUX layer）、Kubernetes（k8s layer）。它根据系统中服务和指标的角色和职责将其组织到不同的层次。SkyWalking 为每个层提供了一套监控和诊断工具，但层之间存在 gap，无法轻松跨层桥接数据。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在 SkyWalking 10 中，SkyWalking 提供了跨层跳转/连接的新功能，为用户提供无缝的监控体验。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;layer-jump&#34;&gt;Layer Jump&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在拓扑图中，用户可以点击服务节点跳转到另一层服务的仪表板。下图显示了通过点击拓扑节点从 GENERAL 层服务拓扑跳转到 VIRTUAL_DATABASE 服务层仪表板的过程。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;layer_jump.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;图 1: Layer Jump&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;layer_jump2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;图 2: Layer jump Dashboard&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;service-hierarchy&#34;&gt;Service Hierarchy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SkyWalking 10 引入了一个新概念，称为 Service Hierarchy，它定义了各层中现有逻辑相同服务的关系。OAP 将检测不同层次的服务，并尝试建立连接。用户可以点击任何层的服务拓扑节点或服务仪表板中的 Hierarchy Services 获取 Hierarchy Topology。在此拓扑图中，用户可以看到不同层次服务之间的关系和指标摘要，并且可以跳转到该层的服务仪表板。当服务发生性能问题时，用户可以轻松分析不同层次的指标并找出根本原因：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;以下是 Service Hierarchy 关系的示例：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;应用程序 &lt;code&gt;song&lt;/code&gt; 同时在 Kubernetes 集群中部署了 SkyWalking agent 和 Service Mesh。因此，应用程序 &lt;code&gt;song&lt;/code&gt; 跨越了 GENERAL、MESH、MESH_DP 和 K8S_SERVICE 层，SkyWalking 可以监控这些层次，Service Hierarchy 拓扑如下：&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;song.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;图 3: Service Hierarchy Agent With K8s Service And Mesh With K8s Service&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;还可以有 Service Instance Hierarchy 拓扑来获取跨层的单实例状态，如下所示：    &lt;img src=&#34;song_instance.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;图 4: Instance Hierarchy Agent With K8s Service(Pod)&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;在 Kubernetes 集群中部署并由应用程序 &lt;code&gt;song&lt;/code&gt; 使用的 PostgreSQL 数据库 &lt;code&gt;psql&lt;/code&gt;。因此，数据库 &lt;code&gt;psql&lt;/code&gt; 跨越 &lt;code&gt;VIRTUAL_DATABASE&lt;/code&gt;、&lt;code&gt;POSTGRESQL&lt;/code&gt; 和 &lt;code&gt;K8S_SERVICE&lt;/code&gt; 层，SkyWalking 可以监控这些层次，Service Hierarchy 拓扑如下：&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;postgre.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;图 5: Service Hierarchy Agent(Virtual Database) With Real Database And K8s Service&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;有关更多支持的层次以及如何检测不同层次服务之间的关系，请参阅 &lt;a href=&#34;https://skywalking.apache.org/docs/main/latest/en/concepts-and-designs/service-hierarchy/#service-hierarchy&#34;&gt;Service Hierarchy&lt;/a&gt;。有关如何在 SkyWalking 中配置 Service Hierarchy，请参阅 &lt;a href=&#34;https://skywalking.apache.org/docs/main/latest/en/concepts-and-designs/service-hierarchy-configuration/&#34;&gt;Service Hierarchy Configuration&lt;/a&gt; 部分。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;使用-ebpf-监控-kubernetes-网络流量&#34;&gt;使用 eBPF 监控 Kubernetes 网络流量&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在之前的版本中，SkyWalking 提供了 &lt;a href=&#34;https://skywalking.apache.org/docs/main/latest/en/setup/backend/backend-k8s-monitoring-metrics-cadvisor/&#34;&gt;来自 kube-state-metrics 和 cAdvisor 的 Kubernetes (K8s) 监控&lt;/a&gt;，它可以监控 Kubernetes 集群状态和 Kubernetes 资源的指标。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在 SkyWalking 10 中，通过利用 &lt;a href=&#34;https://skywalking.apache.org/docs/skywalking-rover/latest/readme/&#34;&gt;Apache SkyWalking Rover&lt;/a&gt; 0.6+，SkyWalking 具有使用 eBPF 监控 Kubernetes 网络流量的能力，可以收集和映射 Kubernetes 环境中应用程序的访问日志。通过这些数据，SkyWalking 可以从 Kubernetes 角度分析和提供服务流量、拓扑、TCP/HTTP 级别指标。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;下图显示了 Kubernetes 网络流量的拓扑和 TCP 仪表板：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;k8s_topology.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;图 6: Kubernetes Network Traffic Topology&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;k8s_dashboard.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;图 7: Kubernetes Network Traffic TCP Dashboard&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;有关如何使用 eBPF 监控 Kubernetes 网络流量的更多详细信息，请参阅 &lt;a href=&#34;https://skywalking.apache.org/blog/2024-03-18-monitor-kubernetes-network-by-ebpf/&#34;&gt;使用 eBPF 监控 Kubernetes 网络流量&lt;/a&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;banyandb---原生-apm-数据库&#34;&gt;BanyanDB - 原生 APM 数据库&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://skywalking.apache.org/docs/skywalking-banyandb/latest/readme/&#34;&gt;BanyanDB&lt;/a&gt; 0.6.0 和 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apache/skywalking-banyandb-java-client&#34;&gt;BanyanDB Java 客户端&lt;/a&gt; 0.6.0 随 SkyWalking 10 一起发布。作为 SkyWalking 的原生存储解决方案，BanyanDB 将成为 SkyWalking 的下一代存储解决方案。推荐在 0.6 到 1.0 期间用于中等规模的部署。
它展示了高性能改进的潜力。与 Elasticsearch 在同一规模下相比，CPU 使用率降低 50%，内存使用率降低 50%，磁盘使用量减少 40%。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;apache-rocketmq-服务器监控&#34;&gt;Apache RocketMQ 服务器监控&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apache RocketMQ 是一个开源的分布式消息和流平台，广泛应用于互联网、大数据、移动互联网、物联网等领域。SkyWalking 为 RocketMQ 提供了一个基本的监控仪表板，包括以下指标：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cluster Metrics：包括当天产生/消费的消息数、总生产者/消费者 TPS、生产者/消费者消息大小、截至昨天产生/消费的消息数、最大消费者延迟、最大 commitLog 磁盘比、commitLog 磁盘比、拉取/发送线程池队列头等待时间、topic count 和 broker count。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Broker Metrics：包括生产/消费 TPS、生产者/消费者消息大小。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Topic Metrics：包括最大生产者/消费者消息大小、消费者延迟、生产/消费 TPS、生产/消费偏移、生产/消费消息大小、消费者组数和代理数。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;下图显示了 RocketMQ Cluster Metrics 仪表板：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;rocket_mq.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;图 8: Apache RocketMQ 服务器监控&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;有关 RocketMQ 监控的更多指标和详细信息，请参阅 &lt;a href=&#34;https://skywalking.apache.org/docs/main/latest/en/setup/backend/backend-rocketmq-monitoring/&#34;&gt;Apache RocketMQ 服务器监控&lt;/a&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;clickhouse-server-监控&#34;&gt;ClickHouse Server 监控&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ClickHouse 是一个开源的列式数据库管理系统，可以实时生成分析数据报告，广泛用于在线分析处理 (OLAP)。ClickHouse 监控提供了 ClickHouse 服务器的指标、事件和异步指标的监控，包括以下部分的指标：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Server Metrics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Query Metrics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Network Metrics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Insert Metrics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replica Metrics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MergeTree Metrics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ZooKeeper Metrics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Embedded ClickHouse Keeper Metrics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;下图显示了 ClickHouse Cluster Metrics 仪表板：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;clickhouse.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;图 9: ClickHouse 服务器监控&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;有关 ClickHouse 监控的更多指标和详细信息，请参阅 &lt;a href=&#34;https://skywalking.apache.org/docs/main/latest/en/setup/backend/backend-clickhouse-monitoring/&#34;&gt;ClickHouse 服务器监控&lt;/a&gt;，以及一篇可以帮助快速入门的博客 &lt;a href=&#34;https://skywalking.apache.org/blog/2024-03-12-monitoring-clickhouse-through-skywalking/&#34;&gt;通过 SkyWalking 监控 ClickHouse&lt;/a&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;apache-activemq-服务器监控&#34;&gt;Apache ActiveMQ 服务器监控&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apache ActiveMQ Classic 是一个流行且强大的开源消息和集成模式服务器。SkyWalking 为 ActiveMQ 提供了一个基本的监控仪表板，包括以下指标：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cluster Metrics：包括内存使用率、写入/读取速率和平均/最大写入持续时间。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Broker Metrics：包括节点状态、连接数、生产者/消费者数和代理下的写入/读取速率。根据集群模式，一个集群可以包含一个或多个代理。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Destination Metrics：包括生产者/消费者数、不同状态的消息、队列和队列/主题中的入队持续时间。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;下图显示了 ActiveMQ Cluster Metrics 仪表板：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;active_mq.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;图 10: Apache ActiveMQ 服务器监控&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;有关 ActiveMQ 监控的更多指标和详细信息，请参阅 &lt;a href=&#34;https://skywalking.apache.org/docs/main/latest/en/setup/backend/backend-activemq-monitoring/&#34;&gt;Apache ActiveMQ 服务器监控&lt;/a&gt;，以及一篇可以帮助快速入门的博客 &lt;a href=&#34;https://skywalking.apache.org/blog/2024-04-19-monitoring-activemq-through-skywalking/&#34;&gt;通过 SkyWalking 监控 ActiveMQ&lt;/a&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;支持多标签名称&#34;&gt;支持多标签名称&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在 SkyWalking 10 之前，SkyWalking 不会在指标数据中存储标签名称，这使得 MQE 必须使用 &lt;code&gt;_&lt;/code&gt; 作为通用标签名称，无法使用多个标签名称查询指标数据。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SkyWalking 10 支持在指标数据中存储标签名称，MQE 可以使用多个标签名称查询或计算指标数据。例如：&lt;code&gt;k8s_cluster_deployment_status&lt;/code&gt; 指标具有 &lt;code&gt;namespace&lt;/code&gt;、&lt;code&gt;deployment&lt;/code&gt; 和 &lt;code&gt;status&lt;/code&gt; 标签。如果我们想查询所有 &lt;code&gt;namespace=skywalking-showcase&lt;/code&gt; 和 &lt;code&gt;status=true&lt;/code&gt; 的部署指标值，可以使用以下表达式：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#fff;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34; data-lang=&#34;text&#34;&gt;k8s_cluster_deployment_status{namespace=&amp;#39;skywalking-showcase&amp;#39;, status=&amp;#39;true&amp;#39;}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;相关增强：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;由于在 SkyWalking 9.6.0 中告警规则配置已迁移到 MQE，因此告警规则也支持多标签名称。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PromeQL 服务支持多标签名称查询。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;metrics-grpc-导出器&#34;&gt;Metrics gRPC 导出器&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SkyWalking 10 增强了 &lt;a href=&#34;https://skywalking.apache.org/docs/main/latest/en/setup/backend/exporter/#grpc-exporter&#34;&gt;metrics gPRC exporter&lt;/a&gt;，支持将所有类型的指标数据导出到 gRPC 服务器。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;skywalking-原生-ui-指标查询切换到-v3-api&#34;&gt;SkyWalking 原生 UI 指标查询切换到 V3 API&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SkyWalking 原生 UI 指标查询弃用 V2 API，全部迁移到 &lt;a href=&#34;https://skywalking.apache.org/docs/main/latest/en/api/query-protocol/#v3-apis&#34;&gt;V3 API&lt;/a&gt; 和 &lt;a href=&#34;https://skywalking.apache.org/docs/main/next/en/api/metrics-query-expression/#metrics-query-expressionmqe-syntax&#34;&gt;MQE&lt;/a&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;其他值得注意的增强功能&#34;&gt;其他值得注意的增强功能&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;支持 Java 21 运行时和 oap-java21 镜像用于 Java 21 运行时。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;从镜像中删除 CLI（&lt;code&gt;swctl&lt;/code&gt;）。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;支持更多的 MQE 函数和操作。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;增强原生 UI 并改善用户体验。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;修复了一些 Bug 和 CVE。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
